gre.ac.uk 2014-04-03

# Privacy and cookies - University of Greenwich - University of Greenwich

## Cookies

Cookies are small files placed on your browsing device by the websites you visit to help them improve your browsing experience.

You can find out more about cookies and how they work at the [All About Cookies website](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Essential usage

Some of our services require cookies to be enabled in order to function. These temporary files remember certain information which could not otherwise be stored as you move between pages on our site, e.g. our [on-demand prospectus](http://www.gre.ac.uk/prospectus) uses cookies to remember which of our programmes you have added to your "basket" when you request the prospectus. These cookies are only stored as long as your visit to our site and are not used to track any other information about you.

Our personalised websites (e.g. [Greenwich VIP](http://www.gre.ac.uk/vip)) similarly use cookies to maintain details of your settings between pages, and to provide anonymised data about usage. When you sign in to use these services you are providing consent for these cookies to be set.

Name | Description | Expires  
---|---|---  
SQ_SYSTEM_SESSION | This cookie is set by the software which powers our website and is essential for the operation of the website. No personal information is stored. | When you close your browser  
  
### Improving our service

Google Analytics sets cookies to help us accurately estimate the number of visitors to the website and volumes of usage. This information helps us to improve the future quality of the website.

Name | Description | Expires  
---|---|---  
_utma | Used by Google Analytics to anonymously identify users, so that new visitors and repeat views can be recorded separately. | 2 years  
_utmb | Used by Google Analytics to establish a session. | 30 minutes  
_utmc | When you close your browser  
_utmz | Used by Google Analytics to record information about how a visitor got to the page. This helps us to determine how visitors find the site and how effective the navigation is. | 6 months  
  
You can find out more about the cookies set by Google Analytics, on the [Google website](http://code.google.com/apis/analytics/docs/concepts/gaConceptsCookies.html#cookiesSet).

### Targeted advertising

Like many businesses we use paid advertisements to increase awareness of our services. Some of these advertisements are "targeted" towards people who have viewed our site previously, or have viewed sites relevant to our services.

In order to do this we provide information to the our advertising company, which they use to provide you with advertising that should be more relevant to your interests. We do this by placing a small pixel on certain pages which are read by the advertising company and interact with cookies that have been set on pages where the adverts appear. This information can not be used to identify you personally.

You can find out more about the targeted advertising we use, including how to switch this off in your browser, at the [Specific Media website](http://specificmedia.com/privacy).

## Personal data

The University of Greenwich web pages may in some instances contain personal data. Personal data may include names, contact details, and sometimes photographs. Personal data of students or any person who is not a member of staff at the university will not be placed on the externally facing website without permission. The university aims to ensure that all personal data which is held on the website is kept accurately and up-to-date.

When personal data is collected from individuals via the website, by for instance forms, questionnaires or surveys, the university will provide information about what it will be used for, and if it will be shared with third parties. The data will be collected securely, with due regard for confidentiality. We will only use the personal information to deliver the services offered or requested, or for our lawful, disclosed purposes.

In order to monitor usage of our website, our web servers collect anonymous information such as IP addresses, the browser software used, and dates, times and pages visited. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

By using any of the sites within our website network, or our services, you are agreeing to our collection of necessary personal information about you.

Personal data will always be processed in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. To find out more visit our [Data Protection](http://www.gre.ac.uk/governance/rmo/data_protection) pages. To find out how you can amend any errors in the personal information held about you, please e-mail [compliance@gre.ac.uk](mailto:compliance@gre.ac.uk).

Our website contains links to other websites. This privacy statement only applies to this website, so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy statements.
